Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

Summary

I am a postdoctoral researcher in statistics at HEC Liège and UCLouvain Saint-Louis Brussels, where I contribute to both the ODALON (Open multimodal Data for Automated LOcal News) and Beamm (BElgian Arithmetic Microsimulation Model) projects. Before that, I obtained a PhD in statistics at UCLouvain, where my research focused on survival analysis and biostatistical methods applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my research, I teach statistics and probability at the undergraduate and master's levels as a visiting lecturer at UCLouvain and UNamur.

	Education
2024	PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2016	MSc in econometrics – Maastricht University, Netherlands
2015	MSc in economics – KU Leuven, Belgium
2013	BSc in economics – UCLouvain, Belgium
	Research experience
2024 – Present	Postdoctoral researcher in statistics – HEC Liège & UCLouvain Saint-Louis Brussels, Belgium
2017 - 2024	Doctoral researcher in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
	See all research projects at antoinesoetewey.com/research
	Teaching experience
2024 – Present	Visiting lecturer in statistics – UCLouvain & UNamur, Belgium
2017 - 2024	Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2018 - 2024	Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

Industry experience

2018 – 2024 **Consultant** in statistics and data analysis – SMCS, Belgium

- Statistical consulting for researchers and academics

2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)